Shivani Junawane

4266 Spoleto Circle, Apt No:206, Oviedo, Florida 32765 | <u>junawaneshivani@knights.ucf.edu</u> | +1(407) 733-5867 <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>GitHub</u> | <u>Portfolio</u>

CAREER OBJECTIVE

3 years of experience in working with Opensource software's and direct interactions with clients from IBM and RedHat, handling individual tasks and developing tools in python. I am looking for a **Summer Software Developer Intern/ Machine Learning Intern Role (2022)** with interest in building and deploying machine learning and deep learning models, specifically interested in **Computer Vision** domain.

EDUCATION

University of Central Florida

August 2021-May 2023

Master's in Computer Science (Computer Vision Track)

[GPA - 4.0]

Savitribai Phule Pune University (former University of Pune), India

August 2014-June 2018

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering

[AGGR – 77% (Distinction)]

Coursework: Machine Learning (MS), Computer Vision (MS), Design and Analysis of Algorithms (BS),

Advanced Computer Architecture (MS)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: Python, C, C++, HTML, Shell

- Technical skills: MySQL, Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scikit-learn, Pytorch, Git, OpenCV, System Design
- Cloud Platforms/Technologies: Docker, Kubernetes, OpenShift, Jenkins, Travis, IBM Cloud (basic)
- OS: Ubuntu, RHEL, Linux/Unix, Windows
- Areas of Interests/Knowledge: Machine Learning, Computer Vision, Deep Learning, DevOps
- Certifications: Convolutional Neural Networks (deeplearning.ai), Neural Networks and Deep Learning
 (deeplearning.ai), Machine Learning with Python (IBM), Python for Data Science (IBM), Docker Essentials: A
 Developer Introduction (IBM)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Graduate Teaching Assistant, University of Central Florida

August 2021 - Present

Managing a class of 1000+ students and conducting office hours for problem solving sessions.

Senior Software Engineer, Persistent Systems Ltd

June 2016 – July 2021

- Worked on building and testing of opensource software, interacting with and contributing to the opensource communities.
- Worked on DevOps and Cloud technologies such as Docker, Kubernetes (OpenShift) and Jenkins.
- Received 3 bravo individual awards and recognized as a Top Talent (top 10%) among the employees of my grade for 2 consecutive years.
- Tools Developed:
 - "License Automation" designed to gather license information of all packages installed inside a docker container which
 reduced the team's manual effort by 85%.
 - "README Automation" designed to create README files (using information from GitHub repos, dockerhub.com, etc.) for 300+ docker containers and upload them to hub.docker.com using selenium.
 - "R-CRAN Automation" designed to automatically test 14k+ packages in the CRAN repository on the IBM power architecture. Improved the package pass percentage from 80% to 98%.

Jr. Web Developer Trainee, Bee Logical Software Solutions

June 2016 - July 2016

 Worked on developing website using WordPress, HTML and php for client Lex-Aquilae which is an organization of advocates and consultants.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Image Segmentation on CityScapes dataset (Python, Pytorch, CNN, KNN)

• Trained a UNet model to segment 10 different instance levels like car, pedestrians, etc. and achieved an IOU score of 0.52 on train set

Driver Drowsiness/Fatigue Detection System (Python, OpenCV, Raspberry PI, Ensemble Learning)

• Built a system to detect drowsiness level of a car driver and ring an alarm to regain his attention by using a pre-trained model (Voila Jones) to detect facial features and eye-aspect-ratio calculation.

Movie Recommendation System (Python, Scikit-Learn, SVM, KNN)

• Worked on the Movie Lens dataset and trained multiple models to compare RMSE and MAE scores of predicted ratings.

Linear Regression, K-Means, Canny Edge Detection from Scratch (Python, CNN, NN, Clustering)

• Implemented algorithms from scratch and evaluate on a sample dataset.

YOUTUBE VIDEOS

<u>Creating your own spell checker using Trie</u> <u>Real world applications of stacks and queues</u>

EXTRA-CURRICULAR

- Won **2nd prize** in National Level Programming Competition for girls organized by **ACM-W India** called Lady Ada, wherein I competed with thousands of women coders across India.
- Captained the Women's cricket team of Persistent Systems Ltd for a year.